Guide to the Jacques Barzun Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Jacques Barzun Papers,
ca.1900-1999.
Barzun, Jacques, 1907-
194 linear ft. in 441 boxes; 1 drawer of oversized material; 11 correspondence file boxes (CLOSED); 2 small cartons (CLOSED); and 2 record storage cartons (CLOSED at ReCAP).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
MS#1483
4079628
The correspondence, researach, and teaching files of Jacques Barzin (1907-2012).
Biographical Note
Jacques Barzun was born in a suburb of Paris in 1907 and died in San Antonio, Texax in 2012.
The son of Henri Martin Barzun, a writer and diplomat, and Anna-Rose Barzun, Barzun grew up in the a family milieu which he described as "nursery of living culture". He met many artists and writers of the modernist era, including Marcel Duchamp, Ezra Pound and Jean Cocteau.
As an undergraduate, Barzun was the Columbia University Spectator’s drama critic and editor of Varsity, the literary magazine>. He way also president of the Philolexian Society and class valedictorian.
He taught his first class at Columbia, Contemporary Civilization, after graduating from the college. He later served as a history professor and was well known for his humanities courses, teaching for almost 50 years.
In the 1930s, Barzun taught the first Colloquium on Important Books class, the precursor to Literature Humanities, with Lionel Trilling, and developed the Core Curriculum’s humanities focus.
Barzun served as dean of graduate faculties in the 1950s and then provost from 1958 to 1967. Barzun obtained the rank of University Professor, the highest rank in the University, in 1967.
Barzun was an outspoken critic of American universities and objected to the politicization of the academy. He strongly condemned both student protesters and faculty during the 1968 student riots.
Barzun wrote ober 30 books. Among the notable titles are Teacher in America (1945) and From dawn to decadence: 500 years of cultural triumph and defeat, 1500 to the present (2000).
After retiring from the University in 1975, he remained an advocate for Columbia and the Core Curriculum.
A devoted Dodgers fan who knew the team when it still played at Ebbets Field, Barzun once remarked, “Whoever wants to know the heart and soul of America had better learn baseball.” That quote is now inscribed on the walls of the Baseball Hall of Fame in Cooperstown, N.Y.
He was awarded the Medal of Freedom from President George W. Bush, and was made a chevalier of the Legion of Honor, France’s highest award. He became a U.S. citizen in 1933.
In October 2007, a month before his 100th birthday, Barzun was presented with the Great Teacher Award from the Society of Columbia Graduates. At the event, Professor Emeritus of History Henry Graff called Barzun “the Babe Ruth of humanistic study and teaching.”
Scope and Content
The professional and personal papers of Jacques Barzun.
Arrangement
Selected materials cataloged; remainder arranged. Materials are arranged into three series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: 1976 Gift
Series III: 1977 Gift
Series IV: 1978 Gift
Series V: 1979 Gift
Series VI: 1980 Gift
Series VII: 1981 Gift
Series VIII: December 1981 Gift
Series IX: 1983 Gift
Series X: April 1983 Gift
Series XI: July 1983 Gift
Series XII: November 1984 Gift
Series XIII: 1986-87 Gift
Series XIV: 1988 Gift
Series XV: 1989 Gift
Series XVI: 1990 Gift
Series XVII: 1991 Gift
Series XVIII: 1992 Gift
Series XIX: 1993 Gift
Series XX: 1994 Gift
Series XXI: 1995 Gift
Series XXII: 1996 Gift
Series XXIII: 2000 Gift
Series XXIV: 2001 Gift
Series XXV: Gift of Virginia Xanthos, 1975
Series XXVI: Tape Recordings
Series XXVII: Microfilms
Subjects
American Academy of Arts and Sciences.; Charles Scribner's Sons.; Columbia University.; National Institute of Arts and Letters (U.S.); Peabody Conservatory of Music.; Auchincloss, Louis.; Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh), 1907-1973.; Acheson, Dean, 1893-1971.; Adler, Mortimer Jerome, 1902-2001.; Arendt, Hannah, 1906-1975.; Barber, Samuel, 1910-1981.; Bentley, Eric, 1916-; Berlin, Isaiah, 1909-1997.; Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869.; Bowen, Catherine Drinker, 1897-1973.; Boyle, Kay, 1902-1992.; Bradbury, Ray, 1920-; Brooks, Cleanth, 1906-1994.; Buckley, William F. (William Frank), 1925-2008.; Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947.; Bundy, McGeorge.; Byron, George Gordon Byron, Baron, 1788-1824.; Cage, John.; Campbell, Joseph.; Chambrun, René de, 1906-; Chapman, John Jay, 1862-1933.; Colum, Padraic, 1881-1972.; Cowley, Malcolm, 1898-1989.; Dannay, Frederic, 1905-1982.; Day Lewis, C. (Cecil), 1904-1972.; Diamond, David, 1915-2005.; Diderot, Denis, 1713-1784.; Duchamp, Marcel, 1887-1968.; Drew, Elizabeth.; Eberhart, Richard, 1904-2005.; Edel, Leon, 1907-1997.; Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1888-1965.; Eastman, Max, 1883-1969.; Erskine, John, 1879-1951.; Forster, E. M. (Edward Morgan), 1879-1970.; Fadiman, Clifton, 1904-1999.; Fitts, Dudley, 1903-1968.; Follett, Wilson, 1887-1963.; Freeling, Nicolas.; Galbraith, John Kenneth, 1908-2006.; Galantière, Lewis, 1895-1977.; Gill, Brendan, 1914-1997.; Gallico, Paul, 1897-1976.; Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997.; Hellman, Lillian, 1905-1984.; Hazzard, Shirley, 1931-; Hart, Moss, 1904-1961.; Gold, Herbert, 1924-; Hope, Bob, 1903-2003.; Hicks, Granville, 1901-1982.; Hersey, John, 1914-1993.; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978.; Huxley, Aldous, 1894-1963.; James, William, 1842-1910.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Jarrell, Randall, 1914-1965.; Kissinger, Henry, 1923-; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1902-; Lippmann, Walter, 1889-1974.; Kronenberger, Louis, 1904-; Lowell, Robert, 1917-1977.; McLuhan, Marshall, 1911-; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-; Menuhin, Yehudi, 1916-; Merton, Thomas, 1915-1968.; Meredith, William, 1919-; Markham, Edwin, 1852-1914.; Mielziner, Jo, 1901-; Michener, James A. (James Albert), 1907-; Merwin, W. S. (William Stanley), 1927-; Miller, Henry, 1891-; Motherwell, Robert.; Partridge, Eric, 1894-1979.; Podhoretz, Norman.; Nin, Anaïs, 1903-1977.; Ransom, John Crowe, 1888-1974.; Prokosch, Frederic, 1908-; Praz, Mario, 1896-; Rodgers, Richard, 1902-; Rockefeller, Nelson Aldrich, 1908-1979.; Schlesinger, Arthur Meier, 1917-; Rukeyser, Muriel, 1913-; Snow, C. P. (Charles Percy), 1905-; Shotwell, James Thomson, 1874-1965.; Spender, Stephen, 1909-; Tate, Allen, 1899-; Thomson, Virgil, 1896-; Untermeyer, Louis, 1885-1977.; Trilling. Lionel, 1905-1975.; Warren, Robert Penn, 1905-; Wescott, Glenway, 1901-; Wouk, Herman, 1915-; Wilson, Edmund, 1895-1972.; United States--History.; American literature--20th century.; Associations, institutions, etc.; Crime--Fiction.; Critics.; Culture.; Education--Study and teaching--United States.; French literature.; Historians.; Language and languages--Grammars.; Language and languages--Style.; Learned institutions and societies.; Learning and scholarship.; Music--History and criticism.; Research.; Rhetoric.; Romanticism.; Science.; Societies.; Style, Literary.; Abstracts.; Addresses.; Advertisements.; Affidavits.; Agenda.; Agreements.; Announcements.; Annual reports.; Applications.; Appointment books.; Appointments.; Articles.; Attendance records.; Awards.; Bibliographies.; Bookplates.; Brochures.; Budgets.; Bylaws.; Calling cards.; Certificates.; Contracts.; Curricula.; Curricula vitae.; Diaries.; Dissertations.; Drafts (literary).; Essays.; Examinations.; Festschriften.; Fiction.; Galley proofs.; Grade books.; Greeting cards.; Handbills.; Illustrations.; Indexes.; Interviews.; Invitations.; Itineraries.; Journals.; Lecture notes.; Lectures.; Librettos.; Lists.; Manuscripts (literary).; Menus.; Minutes.; Monographs.; Motion pictures.; Newsletters.; Notebooks.; Notes.; Notices.; Obituaries.; Personnel records.; Petitions.; Phonograph records.; Photographs.; Pictures.; Plaques.; Playbills.; Poems.; Portraits.; Posters.; Press releases.; Proceedings.; Programs.; Proofs.; Prospectuses.; Questionnaires.; Reports.; Resumes.; Reviews.; Schedules.; Scores.; Scrapbooks.; Sheet music.; Speeches.; Surveys.; Syllabi.; Theses.; Timetables.; Transcripts.; Treatises.; Authors.; College teachers; Consultants.; Educators.; Historians.; Intellectuals.; Scholars.; Encyclopaedia Britannica.
Access Restrictions
The Barzun family correspondence is closed.
Permission is required to see the collection. Professor Barzun wishes any scholar requesting access to write him a letter describing the nature of his or her project.
The letters of Lionel Trilling are closed except by permission of Jacques Barzun.
11 correspondence file boxes, 2 small cartons, & 1 tin box are closed.
Acquisition
04/--/1976 M-1976 Barzun, Jacques
12/19/1990 M-90-12-19 Papers Barzun, Jacques Gift
12/18/1991 M-91-12-18 Papers Barzun, Jacques Gift
12/21/1992 M-92-12-21 Papers Barzun, Jacques Gift
12/20/1993 M-93-12-20 Papers Barzun, Jacques Gift
12/15/1994 M-94-12-15 Papers Barzun, Jacques Gift
12/18/1995 M-95-12-18 Papers & books Barzun, Jacques Gift
1996 M-1996 Correspondence & notes Barzun, Jacques Gift
02/08/2000 M-00-02-08 Correspondence & notes Barzun, Jacques Gift
Alternate Formats
W.H. Auden letters are on microfilm.
Gift of Jacques Barzun and others, 1976 to date.
Finding Aid in Repository
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Acheson, Dean Gooderham
  - Adamic, Louis
  - Adler, Mortimer Jerome
  - Amory, Cleveland
  - Aros, Rene
  - Arendt, Hannah
  - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish
  - Astor, Brooke Russell
  - Auchincloss, Louis Stanton
  - Auden, Wystan Hugh
    [On Microfilm]
  - Aury, Dominique
  - Autant-Lara, Edouard Nicolas
  - Baker, Carlos Heard
  - Baldwin, Faith
  - Barber, Samuel
  - Barr, Stringfellow
  - Beard, Charles Austin
  - Beard, Mary Ritter
  - Bell, Quentin
  - Belmont, Eleanor Robson
  - Bentley, Eric Russell
  - Berendsen, Sir Carl August
  - Berenson, Bernard
  - Berle, Adolf Augustus
  - Berlin, Isaiah
  - Bing, Sir Rudolph
  - Black, Hugo La Fayette
  - Blitzstein, Marc
  - Bouche, Louis
  - Boulanger, Nadia
  - Boulton, Laura Craytor
  - Bowen, Catherine Drinker
  - Boyle, Kay
  - Bradbury, Ray Douglas
  - Brewster, Kingman
  - Brogan, Sir Denis William
  - Brooks, Cleanth
  - Brown, John Mason
  - Bryant, Sir Arthur
  - Buckley, William Frank, Jr.
  - Bunche, Ralph Johnson
  - Bundy, McGeorge
  - Burnett, Whit
  - Burns, Arthur F.
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray
  - Cage, John
  - Campbell, Joseph
  - Carter, Elliott
  - Cassini, Igor
  - Chappell, Warren
  - Chiang, Yee
  - Chute, Marchette
  - Chute, Marchette
  - Cohen, Harriet
  - Colum, Padraic
  - Conant, James Bryant
  - Connelly, Marc
  - Connolly, Cyril Vernan
  - Copland, Aaron
  - Cousins, Norman
  - Cowley, Malcolm
  - Cronin, Vincent
  - Dannay, Frederic
  - Day-Lewis, Cecil
  - Deutsch, Babette
  - Devlin, Patrick Arthur Devlin, Baron
  - De Vries, Peter
  - Dewey, Godfrey
  - Diamond, David
  - Divoire, Fernand
  - Dodge, Marcellus Hartley
  - Douglas, Paul Howard
  - Doyle, Adrian Conan
  - Drew, Elizabeth
  - Duchamp, Marcel
  - Duke, Angier Biddle
  - Eastman, Max
  - Eberhart, Richard
  - Edel, Leon
  - Edman, Irwin
  - Eisenhower, Milton Stover
  - Eliot, T. S.
  - Ernst, Morris Leopold
  - Erskine, John
  - Fadiman, Clifton
  - Faulkner, William
  - Fitts, Dudley
  - Forster, E. M.
  - Frank, Waldo
  - Freeling, Nicolas
  - Fry, Varian
  - Galantiere, Lewis
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth
  - Gallico, Paul
  - Gilbert, Michael Francis
  - Gill, Brendan
  - Ginsberg, Allen
  - Gold, Herbert
  - Goodrich, Lloyd
  - Goudeket, Maurice
  - Gruening, Ernest
  - Hand, Learned
  - Hart, Moss
  - Harty, Sir Herbert Hamilton
  - Hazzard, Shirley
  - Hellman, Geoffrey
  - Hellman, Lillian
  - Hersey, John
  - Herter, Christian Archibald
  - Hicks, Granville
  - Hogan, Frank Smithwick
  - Holt, Hamilton
  - Hope, Bob
  - Horgan, Paul
  - Howe, Mark Anthony DeWolfe
  - Howes, Barbara
  - Huebsch, Ben W.
  - Humphrey, Hubert H.
  - Huxley, Aldous
  - Huxley, Sir Julian
  - Jackson, Barbara Ward
  - Jameson, Storm
  - Janeway, Elizabeth Hall
  - Jarrell, Randolph
  - Jarrett, Emmett
  - Johnson, Alvin Saunders
  - Johnson, Lyndon Baines
  - Johnson, Pamela Hansford
  - Johnson, Philip
  - Jones, Ernest
  - Josephson, Matthew
  - Juta, Jan
  - Kefauver, Estes
  - Kellogg, Frank Billings
  - Kennedy, John F.
  - Kermode, John Frank
  - Kissinger, Henry Alfred
  - Kohn, Hans
  - Koussevitsky, Olga Naumoff
  - Kronenberger, Louis
  - La Guardia, Marie Fisher
  - Larronde, Carlos
  - Lax, Robert
  - Leach, Henry Goddard
  - LeClerq, Janques G. C.
  - Lehmann, John
  - Leinsdorf, Erich
  - Levin, Meyer
  - Lindsay, Howard & Cass Canfield
  - Lippmann, Walter
  - lodge, Henry Cabot
  - Lorant, Stefan
  - Lowell, Abbott Lawrence
  - Lowell, Robert
  - Lowry, Malcolm
  - Luce, henry Robinson
  - Lynes, Russell
  - McGinley, Phyllis
  - MacInnes, Helen
  - MacLeish, Ada Hitchcock
  - MacLeish, Archibald
  - McLuhan, Marshall
  - Malone, Dumas
  - Mariano, Nicky
  - Markham, Edwin
  - Marshall, Lenore Guinzburg
  - Mauoris, Andre
  - Mehta, Ved
  - Meiklejohn, Alexander
  - Mellon, Paul
  - Mencken, Henry Louis
  - Menuhin, Yehudi
  - Meredith, William
  - Merton, Thomas
  - Merwin, William Stanley
  - Michener, James Albert
  - Mielziner, Jo
  - Milhaud, Darius
  - Miller, Gilbert
  - Miller, Henry
  - Mirbeau, Octave
  - Montagu, Ashley
  - Montgomery, Robert Bruce
  - Moore, Douglas,SMoore, Marianne Craig
  - Morgenthau, Jans Joachim
  - Morison, Samuel Eliot
  - Moses, Robert
  - Motherwell, Robert
  - Moynihan, Daniel Patrick
  - Murdoch, Iris
  - Nemerov, Howard
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold
  - Nin, Anais
  - O'Gorman, Ned
  - Pack, Robert Morris
  - Paley, William S.
  - Pange, Pauline de Broglie
  - Partridge, Eric
  - Perkins, Maxwell
  - Pincherle, Marc
  - Pivano, Fernanda Sottsass
  - Podhoretz, Norman
  - Polti, Georges
  - Powell, Lewis F., Jr.
  - Praz, Mario
  - Prokosch, Frederic
  - Pryce-Jones, Alan
  - Ransom, John Crowe
  - Raphael, Chaim
  - Read, Sir Herbert
  - Rickover, Hyman George
  - Robinson, Henry Morton
  - Robinson, Jethro
  - Rockefeller, Nelson Aldrich
  - Rodgers, Richard
  - Rolland, Marie
  - Rostow, Walt Whitman
  - Ruggles, Carl
  - Rukeyser, Muriel
  - Russell, John
  - St.John-Stevas, Norman Anthony Francis
  - Salvemini, Gaetano
  - Schlesinger, Arthur Meier, Jr.
  - Schonberg, Harold C.
  - Schuman, William
  - Schuster, Max Lincoln
  - Searle, Humphrey
  - Sedgwick, Ellery
  - Senghor, Leopold Sedar
  - Sessions, Roger
  - Seymour, Whitney North
  - Shapley, Harlow
  - Sherwood, Robert Emmet
  - Shirer, William Lawrence
  - Shotwell, James, Thomson
  - Skouras, Spyros P.
  - Smith, William Jay
  - Snow, C.P.
  - Spender, Stephen
  - Spock, Benjamin
  - Starkie, Enid Mary
  - Steegmuller, Francis
  - Stevenson, Adlai Ewing
  - Stout, Rex Todhunter
  - Strode, Hudson
  - Sulzberger, Arthur Hays
  - Surette, Thomas Whitney
  - Symons, Julian Gustave
  - Tabori, Paul
  - Tate, Allen
  - Tayloe, Deems
  - Tayloe, Telford
  - Thomas, Norman Mattoon
  - Thompson, Randall
  - Thomson, Virgil
  - Tolstoy, Alexandra
  - Trevor-Roper, Hugh Redwald
  - Trilling, Diana Rubin
  - Trilling, Lionel
    [CLOSED]
  - Tugwell, Rexford Guy
  - Untermeyer, Louis
  - Vanderbilt
  - Van Doren, Mark
  - Varese, Edgar
  - Viereck, Peter
  - Villa, Jose Garcia
  - Voirol, Claudine & Sebastien
  - von Braun, Wernher
  - Wagner, Robert Ferdinand
  - Walter, Bruno
  - Warren, Robert Penn
  - Watson-Watt, Sir Robert Alexander
  - Waugh, Evelyn
  - Weidman, Jerome
  - Wescott, Glenway
  - Wheelock, John Hall
  - White, William Anthony Parker
  - Whitney, John Hay
  - Wilson, Edmund
  - Wolfe, Tom
  - Wouk, Herman
  - Wuorinen, Charles
- Series II: 1976 Gift
  - American historians. Correspondence with societies, etc. 1935-1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Introduction to Naval History. Columbia University course and Jacque Barzun’s textbook. 1943-1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Teacher in America. Correspondence, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Teacher in America. Correspondence, 1946-1950 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Teacher in America. Correspondence with publisher, 1936-1948 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - The Authors Guild, 1947-1955 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - The Nation;New Republic; American Scholar. Correspondence, 1935-1946 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Letters: editor. & readers, 1927-1947 (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
  - The Atlantic Monthly. Correspondence, 1945-1947 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Sarah Lawrence College. Mimeography, 1936-1940 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - The French Race (volume I)-Columbia Studies and Council Fellowship, 1930-1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Race: A Study in Modern Superstition (volume II). Correspondence, 1936-1953 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Race -- revision, 1962-1964 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Commonsense. Correspondence, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Notes on courses and miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Introduction to The Later Ego by James Agate. Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Letters to editors, etc, April 1952-March1953 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Walgreen lectures. Correspondence, October 1953-November 1954 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - God’s Country and Mine. Correspondence, December 1953-May 1955 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Faust (Rinehart edition). Correspondence, August 1954-September 1955 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Flaubert’s Dictionary of Accepted Ideas. Correspondence, August 1954-April 1955 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Letters: Editors-Articles & Reviews for The Nation, New Republic,American Scholar. Correspondence, 1946-1950 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Letters: Editors-Other Magazines. Correspondence, 1946-1950 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Harpers book column. Correspondence, March1947-June 1948 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Harpers book column. Correspondence, July 1948-November 1949 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - The Teacher in America: Documents, clippings & notes ca. 1940-1945 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - The Teacher in America: Correspondence, November 1950-1954 (Box 10)
  - Literary Business-Critic at Large, Requests and Replies, October 1949-May 1951 (Box 11)
  - Literary Business -- Periodical Articles, Correspondence, April 1950-July 1951 (Box 11)
  - Literary Business -- Correspondence, March1951-March1952 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Letters to Ed:ltors, March-November 1953 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - The Readers’ Subscription, Inc., November 1951-November 1953 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Letters to editors, November 1953-July 1954 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Diderot: Rameau's Nephew, Correspondence April 1952-February1953 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - The Century Association, July 1953-December 1960 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - God’s Country and Mine, Correspondence December 1953-July 1954 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - The American Scholar, Correspondence, September 1954-July 1956 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - The Readers’ Subscription, Inc, January 1954-February1959 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Dean’s correspondence, genera1, October 1955-September 1956 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Dean’s correspondence,-personal, October 1955-September 1956 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Dean’s-personal correspondence, September 1956-September 1958 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - The House of Intellect. Correspondence, November 1957-December 1959 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - American Historical Association. Correspondence, July 1954-December 1960 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - American Historical Assoc1ation-Committee on Graduate Education. Correspondence &. Interviews, May 1957-October 1959 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Opinions to authors. Correspondence, September 1958-September 1960 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Opinions to publishers. Correspondence, January 1959-December 1960 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Articles & comments. Correspondence, July 1959-December 1960 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Opinions to authors. Correspondence, October 1960-September 1963 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Opinions to publishers. Correspondence, October 1961-December 1962 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Lectures accepted. Correspondence, 1942-January 1956 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Article accepted. Correspondence, September 1954-June 1956 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Lectures declined. Correspondence, September 1956-June 1957 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Articles accepted. Correspondence, September 1956-June 1959 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Articles & comments. Correspondence, September 1956-June 1959 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Critic-General. Correspondence, January 1953-June 1960 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Letures-Comments. Correspondence, January 1956-June 1960 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Lectures accepted. Correspondence, January -December, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Opinions to authors. Correspondence, September 1955-September 1957 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Opinions to publishers. Correspondence, September 1955-September 1958 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Lectures declined. Correspondence, September 1955-September 1958 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Opinions to authors. Correspondence, September 1956-September 1958 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Lectures declined. Correspondence, June 1957-September 1958 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Lectures accepted Correspondence, January 1956-December 1958 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Opinions to publishers. Correspondence, September 1956-January 1959 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Lectures declined. Correspondence, September 1958-July 1959 (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Lectures declined. Correspondence, July -December 1959 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Lectures declined. Correspondence, January -December 1960 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - American Coune1l of Learned Societies, 1952-September 1958 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - The National Institute of Arts and Letters, September 1954-December 1960 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - The American Scholar. Correspondence, July 1956-December 1960 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Articles declined. Correspondence, September 1954-June 1960 (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - Personal correspondence, September 1954-June 1960 (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - Critic-General Correspondence, January 1960-June (Box 24, Folder 38)
  - Lectures, accepted. Correspondence, January 1960-December 1960 (Box 24, Folder 38)
  - The Mid-Century Book Society. Correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 25, Folder 39-40)
  - The Mid-Century Book Society. Correspondence, 1961-1964 (Box 25, Folder 40)
  - The Mid-Century Book Society. Advertisements, 1959-1963 (Box 25, Folder 40)
  - The Mid-Century Book Society. Contracts, correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 25, Folder 41)
  - The Mid-Century Book Society. Facts & figures, 1959-1963 (Box 25, Folder 41)
  - The Mid-Century Book Society. Financial reports, 1959-1962 (Box 25, Folder 41)
  - Articles accepted. Correspondence, June 1959-June 1962 (Box 27, Folder 42)
  - Articles declined. Correspondence, July 1960-December 1963 (Box 27, Folder 42)
  - Articles-comments Correspondence, January 196l-June 1962 (Box 27, Folder 42)
  - Lectures declined. Correspondence, January -December 1961 (Box 27, Folder 38)
  - Personal Invitations, September 1958-December 1962 (Box 28, Folder 43)
  - Personal Correspondence, July 1960-December 1962 (Box 28, Folder 43)
  - Lectures declined. Correspondence, January 1962-.December 1963 (Box 28, Folder 44)
  - Lectures accepted. Correspondence, January 1962-December 1963 (Box 29, Folder 44)
  - Lectures-comments. Correspondence, July 1960.December 1964 (Box 29, Folder 45)
  - Critic-general. Correspondence. July 1961.June 1965 (Box 29, Folder 45)
  - Lectures accepted. Correspondence. January -December 1964 (Box 29, Folder 45)
  - Lectures declined. Correspondence. January -December 1964 (Box 29, Folder 45)
  - Opinions to authors. Correspondence, /010/1963-December 1965 (Box 30, Folder 46)
  - Opinions to publishers. Correspondence, /010/l963-December 1965 (Box 30, Folder 46)
  - Articles-comments. Correspondence, July 1962-December 1965 (Box 30, Folder 47)
  - Articles accepted. Correspondence, July 1962-December 1965 (Box 30, Folder 47)
  - Articles declined. Correspondence, January 1964.December 1965 (Box 30, Folder 47)